One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
Fire!
حريق
Hey, everyone! Get up!
يا رفاق، استيقظوا
Dammit...! Is this the pirates' doing?
سحقًا، أهذا من صنيع القراصنة؟
There's still a bunch of people inside!
لا بدّ أنّه لا يزال الكثير من النّاس في الدّاخل
Where's Mr. Iceburg?! What's going on upstairs?!
أين أيسبرغ-سان؟ ما الّذي يجري في الأعلى؟
Let's go check!
لنذهب للتّفقّد
Hurry! Pitch in and put out the fire!
أسرعوا، أخمدوا النار
It seems the fire has started to spread.
يبدو أنّ النار بدأت تنتشر
I don't care if you're a leopard man or what...
لا أدري إن كنتَ إنسانًا نمرًا ...أم ماذا، لكن
I won't let you lay a hand on Mr. Iceburg!
لن أدعك تمسّ أيسبرغ-سان بسوء
Oh, no...! Carnivore zoan types are more brutal than others!
مصيبة، يصبح مستخدمو نوع زون اللّاحم أكثر عدوانية
That's right. Logia types, zoan types, and paramecia types...
صحيح، أنواع الفواكه هي لوغيا ...وزون وباراميشيا
Their powers are various and unique.
توجد الكثير من القوى الفريدة
But the zoan type is the one that offers pure, physical augmentation.
التعزيز الجسدي الحقيقي هو سمة أنواع زون
The more we train, the more power we gain.
كلّما تدرّبنا، صرنا أقوى
Zoans are head and shoulders above the rest in close-quarters combat.
نوع زون هو أقوى الأصناف عندما يتعلّق الأمر بالهجوم القريب
Mr. Iceburg!
أيسبرغ-سان
Foremen!
رؤساء العمّال
Lucci... the craftsmen are coming upstairs.
لوتشي... إنّ الحرفيّين قادمون إلى الأعلى
Don't worry. They won't get this far.
لا تقلقي، لا يمكنهم الوصول إلى هنا
Tempest Kick!
ساق العاصفة
Go back down! The ceiling's about to...!
...ارجعوا، إنّ السّقف
Nami!
نامي
Chopper!
تشوبّر
Paulie, what're you doing?
باولي، ما الّذي يجري؟
Ain't no way in hell I'm leaving you here!
سأخرجك من هذا المكان مهما كان
You can't! Not with those wounds...!
هذا مستحيل، جراحك بليغة للغاية ...فكيف لك أن
Stop, Paulie.
توقّف يا باولي
Don't say my name... as if we're still friends!
لا تناديني باسمي وكأنّنا صديقان
Damn you...!
...سحقًا لكم
Why did it have to be you guys?!
لِمَ أنتم بالضّبط؟
I...
...أنا
At the very least, I...
...على الأقل
I always thought of you guys as my friends!
اعتبرتكم رفاقي طوال هذا الوقت
The feeling wasn't mutual.
كان ذلك من جانبك فحسب
Pigeon jerk...!
...وغد الحمامة
Straw Hat!
قبّعة القش
Finger Pistol.
مسدّس الإصبع
Luffy!
لوفي
Have a nice flight off the island!
احظَ بتحليق ممتع خارج هذه الجزيرة
You bastard...!
أيّها الوغد
Iron Body.
الجسد الحديدي
Zoro!
زورو
You too.
أنت أيضًا
Did you get everyone out?!
هل أخرجتم الجميع؟
We can't go back inside! Have each team account for its men!
،ما عدنا نستطيع الدخول ليحسب كلّ فريق رجاله
Hey, where's Mr. Iceburg? Did you see him?
مهلاً، أين أيسبرغ-سان؟ هل رأيته؟
Don't tell me he's still in there with that fire...!
...لا يعقل أنّه لا يزال في النيران
I'm sure he's okay!
أنا واثق أنّه بخير
Three foremen were with him; no way they left him behind.
ثلاثة من رؤسائنا معه، محال أنّه بقي هناك
You guys go check over there too!
اذهبوا وتفقّدوا المكان أيضًا
This woman...
...هذه المرأة
She's one of the Straw Hats. I'm sure of it!
إنّها من طاقم قبّعة القشّ ممّا لا شكّ فيه
Did she jump out a window?
هل قفزت من النافذة؟
She must've narrowly escaped when the flames surrounded her.
لا بدّ أنّ النيران أحاطت بها وعانت لكي تهرب
What do we do with her?
ماذا نفعل بها؟
Seriously... They caused this mess.
صدقًا... يا له من فعلٍ مريع
We'll make her tell us where the others are!
سنسألها عن مكان البقية
We'll round up the rest of them and hand them over to the Marines!
سنقبض عليهم جميعًا ونسلّمهم إلى البحريّة
A pirate's word cannot count as evidence.
ما يقوله القراصنة لا يُؤخذ كدليل
This incident will now be shrouded in darkness.
ستُدفن هذه الحادثة في غياهب الظلام
Mr. Iceburg...
...أيسبرغ-سان، مهما كنتَ سفَّانًا شهيرًا
but you, a mere citizen, shouldn't have defied our formidable World Government.
بما أنّك من عامّة الناس، ما كان يجب عليك أن تعصي حكومة العالم القويّة
Let's go. We'll find Tom's other disciple Franky—
...لنذهب، سنجد تلميذ توم الآخر، فرانكي
rather, Cutty Flam, and take the blueprints from him.
أو بالأحرى، كاتي فلام ونأخذ منه المخطّطات
Grandma! Grandma! There's a big fire!
جدّتي، جدّتي، هنالك حريق كبير
That's Galley-La's main office. What a terrible thing to do...
إنّه مكتب غاليلا الرّئيسيّ ...يا له من فعل مريع
A terrible thing? Did someone set the fire?
فعل مريع؟ هل الحريق من صنيع أحد؟
Well, I don't know for certain...
...لا أدري
but often, a bad feeling turns out to be right.
لكنّ الحدس السّيّئ يكون حقيقة أحيانًا
I do hope Iceburg's all right.
آمل أنّ أيسبرغ بخير
Seriously, all this for something that shouldn't even exist in the first place.
،صدقًا، كلّ هذا بسبب ذلك الشّيء لا يجب أن يتواجد
Blueno, you said Franky was at your bar?
بلونو... أكان فرانكي في حانتك؟
Yeah.
نعم
But he ran off to find Straw Hat.
لكنّه هرع للبحث عن قبّعة القش
I see.
...فهمت
Seems like he tends to move about.
يبدو أنّه لا يمكث في مكان واحد طويلاً
But someone's sure in the wrong place at the wrong time.
لكن ثمّة أشخاص يختارون توقيتًا سيّئًا
Take a gander.
انظر
Listen, Straw Hat!
اسمع يا قبّعة القش
We've got long nose!
لقد قبضنا على طويل الأنف
That's right, we do!
أجل، إنّه معنا
If you don't want us to sew him to a tree–
...إن كنت لا تريده أن يغرق في النّهر
Idiot! How do you not get it yet?
غبي، ليس هكذا، كم مرّة يجب أن أخبرك؟
It's, "If you don't want us to throw him in the sea!"
"بل "إن كنت لا تريده أن يغرق في البحر
Sew him in–
...في النهر
Throw him!
"في البحر"
Dammit, do you even listen?!
تبًّا، ما الّذي تنصت له؟
All that matters is getting the message to Straw Hat, right?
الأهم هو إيصال الرسالة إلى قبّعة القش، صحيح؟
But that message ain't gonna work!
أخبرناك أنّ تلك الرسالة لن تفلح
Bro's gonna beat you up.
سيوسعك أخانا ضربًا
"If you don't want us to throw him in the sea,
يجب أن تقول، "إن كنت لا تريده "أن يغرق في البحر
come to the warehouse under the bridge! From, Franky!"
تعال إلى المستودع أسفل الجسر "مع تحيات فرانكي
Got that?!
مفهوم؟
Even if he does come, Bro's still gonna beat the piss outta him.
ناهيك أنّه حتّى إن أتى، سيوسعه أخي ضربًا
Who did you say is waiting for whom and where?
قلتَ من ينتظر من وأين؟
Hmm? Who the hell are you?!
من أنت؟
We're in the middle of something, so scram!
نحن مشغولون الآن، انصرف
Unless you want to die, you have three seconds to answer.
،إن كنتم لا تريدون الموت أجيبوا عن سؤالي بعد ثلاث ثوانٍ
This guy's talking outta his ass.
هذا الشخص يتفوّه بالهراء
Don't you know who we are?
هل تعرف إلى أيّ عائلة ننتمي؟
Where is this warehouse under the bridge?
أيّ مكان تقصده بالمستودع الّذي أسفل الجسر؟
Franky is there, isn't he?
فرانكي هناك، أليس كذلك؟
What business do you have with Bro?
أيّ شأن تملك مع أخي؟
If you wanna talk to him, then you're gonna talk to us first.
إن كنت تريد الحديث معه فعليك الحديث معنا أوّلاً
I can't believe you and your East Blue friends came all this way just to split up over a ship!
لا أصدّق أنّك تترك رفاقك الّذين ارتحلت معهم
Why are you guys crying?
لماذا تبكون؟
Don't be dumb! We're not crying, dummy!
غبي، لا نبكي يا غبي
It was just so moving that you stuck it out with your ship even with everything going on!
لكن صحيحٌ أنّني تأثّرت بحمايتك لهذه السّفينة وحدك
– We're not crying!
لسنا نبكي، لا أحد منّا يبكي
What the heck is their problem?
ما بالهم؟
Anyway, you gotta realize I'm not friends with those guys anymore, right?
على أيّ حال، بتّم تعرفون الآن أنّ أولئك الأشخاص لم يعودوا رفاقي، صحيح؟
Here's...
...سوف
Here's a little ditty about your hardships!
أغنّي من أجل صِعابك
It's called, "Falling Out: Northern Wind Chop!"
،عنوان الأغنية هو "صداقة مقطوعة "رياح الشمال القاطعة
– Yay! Bro!
مرحى يا أخي
Are you making fun of me?!
هل تسخر منّي؟
Hey, is the tea ready yet? I'm thirsty.
هل الشاي جاهز؟ أشعر بالعطش
– All done! Coming right up!
حسنًا، سنحضره حالاً
I'm exhausted from crying... Not that I was crying, though.
أنهكني البكاء... ليس وكأنّني بكيت
Here you go, Bro. It's a little hot.
تفضّل يا أخي، إنّه حامٍ قليلاً
Thanks.
شكرًا
All right, I get it, little bro. You know...
...فهمتُ إذًا يا أخي
Ouch, it's hot!
هذا مؤلم، إنّه ساخن
Settle down a little, will you?!
هلاّ هدأت قليلاً؟
Sorry 'bout that, Bro.
أنا آسفة يا أخي
Why don't you take a break and have some tea, too?
ما رأيك أن تأخذ استراحة وتحتسي بعض الشاي أيضًا؟
I can't blame you.
لا ألومك
You must hold quite the grudge against us for stealing your 200 million belly...
لا بدّ أنّك تكنّ ضغينة كبيرة تجاهنا
especially since it led to such a big fight.
بما أنّ ذلك قاد إلى شجار كبير
What happened, happened.
كان ذلك مقدّرًا فحسب
Holding a grudge won't do me any good.
لن تفيدني الضّغينة في شيء
Y'know, you're all right.
تملك روحًا رياضية
I dig it.
...فهمت
But that 200 million...
...بشأن الـ200 مليون
We spent it all!
أسرفتها كلّها
I'll knock you flat on your ass.
هل تريدني أن أضربك؟
Now, now... Cool your jets.
هوّن عليك... لا تغضب هكذا
You've shown me how manly you are.
أريتني مدى رجولتك
So that means I have no room to be upset over how my home and dismantling yard—
لذا عليّ الآن أن أهدّئ أعصابي بسبب الدمار الكامل
my beloved Franky House— was completely and utterly destroyed!
لمنزل فرانكي، الّذي كان منزلي ومصنع التّهديم
And then you guys beat my underlings to a pulp!
علاوةً على ذلك، قضيتم على أتباعي
Why, you rotten bastards...!
كيف تجرؤون أيّها الأوغاد؟
Bro!
أخي
The anger came out!
لقد تصاعد غضبك
You bastards!
أوغاد
Y'know, little bro, a lot's happened,
إذًا يا أخي، مع أنّ الكثير حدث
but we should stop being angry with one another
دعنا نهدّئ غضبنا تجاه بعضنا البعض في هذه المسألة
and let dragons eat dragons.
ونحلّ الخلاف بالتّمادي
You mean "let bygones be bygones."
تقصد بالتّراضي
Yeah, it's "let bygones be bygones," Bro.
تقصد بالتّراضي يا أخي
Any plans now that you're on your own?
ماذا سنفعل الآن بما أنّك وحدك؟
You don't have anywhere to go, right?
ليس لديك مكان تقصده، صحيح؟
If not, I can take you in. Come work for me!
،في تلك الحالة، يمكنني أن أضمّك لي اعمل لصالحي
I like you.
أُعجبت بك
Forget it! I don't wanna dismantle ships.
مستحيل، لا أريد أن أصبح عامل هدم
Sure, I left my crew, but I'm still a pirate!
مع أنّني تركتُ مجموعتي، إلّا أنّي لا أزال قرصانًا
Here's one I call, "Pirate's Creed."
،استمعوا لأغنيّتي رجاءً "بعنوان "قانون القراصنة
– Yay, Bro!
مرحى، أخي
You're making fun of me again!
سأسألك ثانيةً، هل تسخر منّي؟
C'mon... I'm just trying to help you figure out what to do next!
يا إلهي... إنّي أحاول أن أفكّر فيمَ يجب أن تفعل تاليًا من أجل مصلحتك
It's none of your business!
ذلك ليس من شأنك
Besides, is this the best place to relax right now?
وأيضًا، ألا بأس أن تسترخي في مكان كهذا؟
A storm surge is coming soon, right?
ثمّة موجة عارمة تقترب، صحيح؟
Yeah, that's exactly why...
...أجل، ولهذا السّبب بالذّات
when Aqua Laguna comes, we all have to help each other.
،عندما تحلّ علينا أكوا لاغونا علينا مساعدة بعضنا
As the night rolls on, the sea will reach the second floor of most homes.
من الآن حتّى وقت متأخر من الليل
Right now, anyone in the Backstreets or on the cape won't stand a chance.
إن كنتَ في الشوارع الخلفية أو الرّؤوس في وقتٍ كهذا، فأنت هالك لا محالة
You won't have to worry if you leave your ship here.
لست بحاجة للقلق إن تركت سفينتك هنا أيضًا
Oh... Thanks... I appreciate it.
شكرًا... أقدّر لك ذلك
You jerk! Don't be so cold!
أيّها الغبي، لا تتكلّم وكأنّنا غريبين عن بعضنا
Man, It's gotta be tough to deal with flood damage every year.
على أيّ حال، لا بدّ أنّ من الصعب أن تتضرّروا من الفيضان هكذا كلّ عام
Well, at this point, everyone's used to this annual evacuation.
الجميع معتادون على هذا الإخلاء السنوي على كلّ حال
The bigger problem is how the sea level rises with every year.
الإشكال الأكبر هو أنّ مستوى ماء البحر كان يتزايد كلّ عام
The Backstreets district that's visible above the sea
المنطقة الخلفيّة الّتي ترونها فوق البحر الآن هي في الواقع بلدة بُنيت على أسطح
It's said that Shipyard Island and the Backstreets were once on the same landmass.
يقال أنّ جزيرة السفانة والشوارع الخلفيّة
But now, enough of the island has been submerged that's it's called a floating city.
لكن باتت منطقة كبيرة منها غارقة تحت الماء وسُمّيت بالمدينة العائمة
The sidewalks became canals.
أصبحت كلّ الأرصفة قنوات
Technically, it's not the water level that's increasing,
بالأحرى، بدلاً من القول أنّ مستوى الماء في ازدياد
but rather, the island's foundation is sinking.
نقول أنّ أساس الجزيرة يغرق
At this rate, there won't be many places left to live in town.
على هذا الحال، المناطق الّتي نعيش فيها في البلدة ستتقلّص شيئًا فشيئًا
Huh... So even this gorgeous, floating city has its own share of hardships.
فهمت... حتّى هذه المدينة العائمة الجميلة تمرّ بأزمات إذًا
But if push comes to shove, you can take the sea train and go live somewhere else.
لكن، إن اقتضت الحاجة
That's certainly an option... Well, now it is, anyway.
بإمكانك قول ذلك الآن
But the sea train has only existed for a little over a decade.
لكنّ القطار البحري لم يُخترع إلّا قبل نحو عقد
Before then, it wasn't so simple to just up and travel across the sea.
قبل ذلك الوقت، لم يكن التّنقّل عبر البحر سهلًا
Naturally, it was rare to see folks travel between islands.
بطبيعة الحال، قلّما استطاع الناس التّنقّل بين الجزر
The island existed in isolation,
ففي هذه الجزيرة المعزولة
What eased peoples' fears about the future
وما طمأن قلوب النّاس حول المستقبل
was the sea train, Puffing Tom.
كان القطار البحري، توم النّافث
You could now cross the sea whenever you wanted without a log pose.
بإمكانهم الآن عبور البحر متى أرادوا دون الحاجة إلى بوصلة مسجّلة
This was some real progress!
لذا كان ذلك بمثابة تقدّم كبير
It's all thanks to the sea train's creator, a great shipwright named Tom.
كلّ ذلك بفضل السفان العظيم توم الّذي صنع القطار البحري
He saved all of us.
لقد أنقذنا جميعًا
Bro!
أخي
Help...
...النجدة
I'll say hello to "Bro" for you.
سألقي التحيّة على أخيكم من أجلكم
We have the location.
نعرف موقعه الآن
Let's go.
هيّا بنا
Ouch!
هذا مؤلم
So, little bro...
...إذًا يا أخي
I'm gonna cut to the chase.
سأدخل في صلب الموضوع
What're you gonna do after you fix that ship?
ماذا ستفعل بعد إصلاحك لتلك السّفينة؟
What am I gonna do?
وماذا في رأيك؟
I'll go on adventures with her again,
بالطبع سأذهب في مغامرة معها ثانيةً
and someday we'll go back to our home, the East Blue!
ثمّ سأعود إلى دياري يومًا، في الأزرق الشرقي
It's not like we made it around the world,
ليس وكأنّنا جبنا العالم
but this is a ship that went to the Grand Line.
لكنّ هذه سفينة ذهبت إلى الغراند لاين
That should be good enough to call it a triumphant return.
ستكون جيّدة لدرجة أن تسمّيها عودة منتصرة
I'll hold my head up and–
...سأرفع رأسي عاليًا و
Nope! There's no going back...
...كلّا، لن تستطيع العودة
to the East Blue.
إلى الأزرق الشرقي
It's just too far.
إنّه بعيد جدًّا من الأساس
Bro?
أخي؟
When we pulled up the ship earlier,
عندما رفعنا السّفينة سابقًا
I looked her over real good.
كنتُ أراقبها عن كثب
That ship is at the end of her life.
وصلت تلك السّفينة إلى نهايتها
Galley-La's assessment is spot-on.
تقييم غاليلا صحيح
Take it from a dismantler...
بصفتي شخصًا يزاول عمل التّهديم
I suggest dismantling her.
أقترح عليك تهديمها
What...? That's ridiculous!
ماذا؟ هذا سخيف
I'll help you demolish your ship!
سأساعدك على تهديم سفينتك
What?! What're you saying, you jerk?!
ماذا؟ ما الّذي تقوله أيّها النّذل؟
Wait! What're you doing?!
انتظر، ما الّذي تفعله؟
Stop right there!
توقّف عندك
– Bro!
أخي
It's just a friendly offer to help scrap your ship.
قلت توًّا أنّني سأساعدك على تهديم تلك السّفينة
Don't be ridiculous! I won't let you!
لا تكن سخيفًا، لن أسمح بذلك
The Merry is my ship!
الميري هي سفينتي
She's not! In fact...
...لا... بل
she's no longer a ship.
لم تعد سفينةً
What'd you say?!
ماذا قلت؟
I asked you earlier what you were gonna do after you fixed this ship, didn't I?
سألتك قبل قليل ماذا تنوي أن تفعل بعد أن تصلح هذه السّفينة، صحيح؟
If you were going to head out to sea to die with this ship,
لو أنّك أجبتني أنّك ستهب حياتك إلى البحر مع هذه السّفينة
I wouldn't have said anything.
لما قلتُ شيئًا
But... you said that you wanted to go back to the East Blue on this ship.
لكن... قلت أنّك تريد أن تعود إلى الأزرق الشرقي على متن هذه السّفينة
So I'm stopping you here and now... little bro.
لذا أحاول أن أوقفك... يا أخي
This ship... won't even make it to the next island.
ما عادت هذه السّفينة... تستطيع حتّى أن تصل للشاطئ التّالي
Listen. Ships are born with the promise to carry you across the sea
اسمع، تولد السّفن مع وعد
from one shore to another.
أن تحملك عبر البحر من شاطئ إلى آخر
In other words, once a ship can no longer carry you to shore...
بعبارات أخرى، عندما لا تستطيع ...السّفينة حملك إلى شاطئ
Hey!
مهلاً
Stop it!
توقّف
Once she can't carry you to shore...
...عندما لا تستطيع حملك إلى شاطئ
she's no longer a ship!
لا تظلّ سفينةً
– Bro!
أخي
Stop it!
توقّف
You bastard! Get away from the Merry!
أيّها الوغد، ابتعد عن ميري
You damn blockhead!
أيّها الحقير
If you won't listen...
...إن كنت لا تفهم
then take a good look at her...
ألقِ نظرة جيّدة عليها... بعينيك
Sorry, Merry.
آسف يا ميري
I'll fix you right away.
سأصلحك على الفور
I'll fix you right away... I'll do it...
...سأصلحك على الفور... سوف
as many times as you need...
...كلّما احتجت
I'll fix you as many times as you need!
سأصلحك كلّما احتجت لذلك
As many times as you need!
كلّما احتجت لذلك
Hey! Enough already, long nose!
أنت، يكفي يا طويل الأنف
You saw the bottom of the ship, right?!
رأيت أسفل السّفينة، صحيح؟
With a broken keel, the outer panels are breaking free, and the frames are in shambles!
بكون العارضة الّتي في جذرها مكسورة
A ship like that falls apart from the outside with each wave.
عندما تكون السّفينة في تلك الحالة ستتداعى ببساطة من الخارج مع كلّ موجة
And yet, a total amateur like you thinks you can–
...ومع ذلك، تظنّ أنّ هاوٍ مثلك يستطيع
Just shut up already!
اخرس
I don't want you to tell me anything!
لا أريدك أن تخبرني أيّ شيء
Shut your mouth or I'll shut it for you, you damn thug!
أطبق فمك وإلاّ أوسعتك ضربًا أيّها المشاغب
Deep...
...في قرارة
Deep down...
...نفسي
I already knew...
أنا أعلم
Huh?! What did you say?!
ماذا؟ ماذا قلت؟
Deep down...
...في قرارة نفسي
Deep down... I already knew.
أعلم كلّ شيء... في قرارة نفسي
I know that Merry is at the end of her life!
أعلم أنّ ميري وصلت لنهاية حياتها
Deep down...
...في قرارة نفسي
I... knew...
...أنا... أعلم
When I heard the assessment...
عندما سمعتُ التّقييم
I was finally convinced that what I saw back then really happened.
اقتنعتُ أنّ ما رأيته ذلك اليوم حدث فعلاً
At first, I thought I was dreaming.
ظننتُ أنّني أحلم في البداية
I thought, "What I'm seeing can't be real."
فكّرتُ أنّه من المستحيل أن يحدث شيء كذلك
On a foggy night... in a forest under the moonlight,
في ليلةٍ ضبابيّة... في غابة تحت ضوء القمر
I heard the strikes of a wooden hammer.
سمعتُ دقّات مطرقة خشبيّة
It came from the ship, even though no one was supposed to be on board.
صوت صادر من السّفينة
That sound was coming from our battered, grounded ship.
أتى الصّوت من سفينتنا، الّتي تكبّدت أضرارًا بعد أن هُمّشت في الشاطئ
Despite how thick the fog was, I definitely saw someone there,
كان الجوّ ضبابيًّا جدًّا، لكنّي رأيتُ ...أحدهم هناك بكلّ تأكيد
using a wooden hammer.
يدقّ بمطرقة خشبيّة
I just... couldn't figure out who it was.
لم أعرف من يكون
But then, when morning came,
لكن، عندما حلّ صباح اليوم التّالي
though the work was lousy, the ship was fixed.
أُصلحت السّفينة بشكلٍ رديء
The broken mast was also restored to its former shape.
كما أُصلح الصّاري المكسور كليًّا ليعود كما كان
But the real mystery was that...
...لكنّ الشّيء الأكثر غموضًا
whoever fixed the Merry knew her original design.
أيًّا كان من أصلح الميري، كان يعرف كيف كانت تبدو في الأصل
Despite how much we had refitted her,
على الرّغم من أنّنا أضفنا العديد من التعديلات
someone restored the Merry to how she used to look!
أعاد ذلك الشّخص الميري لسابق عهدها
It was all a big mystery to us, but...
...شكّل كلّ شيء غموضًا بالنّسبة لنا، لكن
for some reason, their words remained in my heart.
لسببٍ ما، ظلّت هذه الكلمات في قلبي
I don't know if the person I saw actually said them, or if I was imagining things...
لا أدري حتّى إن كانت من قول ...ذلك الشّخص أو من نسج خيالي
Don't worry.
لا تقلق
I'll carry you guys for a little bit longer.
سأحملكم لوقتٍ أطول قليلاً
This may sound stupid, but...
...قد يبدو هذا غبيًّا، لكن
I bet she was already at her limits back then.
أراهن أنّ السّفينة كانت قد وصلت إلى حدّها بالفعل
So she might've assumed that form to let us know.
لذا ربّما تحوّلت إلى ذلك الشّكل لتُبلغنا
When I heard the assessment, that's all I thought about.
هذا ما تبادر إلى ذهني عندما سمعتُ التقييم
You think I'm crazy, don't you? You don't have to believe me.
تظنّ أنّني مجنون، أليس كذلك؟ لست بحاجة لتصديقي
Bro?
أخي؟
Believe you...?
أصدّقك؟
This person looked like a sailor holding a wooden hammer, right?
بدا ذلك الشخص كبحّار يحمل مطرقة خشبيّة، صحيح؟
What...? Why...?
ماذا...؟ لماذا...؟
Do you know?
هل تعرف؟
Little bro...
...يا أخي
you saw a klabautermann.
رأيتَ كلاباوترمان
K-Klabau...?
كـ-كلاباو...؟
The klabautermann.
كلاباوترمان
It's a legend known among sailors.
إنّها إحدى الأساطير المعروفة لدى البحّارة
It's a sprite that only lives in ships treated with great care.
إنّها جنيّة تقطن فقط في السّفينة الّتي تلقى عناية فائقة
So yeah, it's like a ship's incarnation.
بإمكانك القول أنّها تجسيد للسّفينة
They carry a wooden hammer and wear a sailor's raincoat.
تحمل مطارق خشبيّة في أيديها
When danger approaches,
عندما يقترب الخطر من السّفينة
they run around inside the ship to inform the crew.
تجري داخل السّفينة لتبلغ الناس عن دنوّه
It's said that they sometimes help sailors in big ways.
ويقال أنّها تساعد البحّارة أحيانًا إلى حدّ كبير
But honestly, this is the first time I've heard someone say they saw one.
لكن لأصدقك القول، هذه أوّل مرّة أسمع أحدًا رآها
The more care the ship receives, the more it appreciates its crew.
،كلّما عومِلَت السّفينة بعناية قدّرت ذلك للبحّارة
This ship must've wanted to make sure you made it to the next island.
على الأغلب أنّ هذه السّفينة أرادت حملكم إلى الشاطئ الآخر بطريقةٍ ما
She encountered a crew she wanted to carry so badly
استطاعت أن تلتقي بطاقم أرادت حمله بشدّة
that she took the form of a human.
...لدرجة أنّها ستستعير شكل إنسان لتظهر
I bet she's been very happy.
لا بدّ أنّها كانت سعيدة للغاية
Merry...
...ميري
I see...
...فهمت
Then, the one...
...إذًا، من
who talked to me then...
...تحدّث إليّ حينها
really was you, huh?
كان أنت، صحيح؟
Merry...
...ميري
But you've gotta be kidding me...
...لكنّ هذا ضربٌ من الجنون
You had a big fight with your friends even though you knew the ship was at her limits?
هل خضت شجارًا عنيفًا مع رفاقك لأنّك عرفت بحالة سفينتك الميؤوسة؟
It's not that simple.
الأمر ليس بتلك البساطة
Men are so inept!
كم الرّجال خُرّق
They're morons!
إنّهم حمقى
Looks like someone's here.
يبدو أنّ أحدهم أتى
"Someone's here"? It's gotta be Zambai and the boys!
أحدهم أتى"؟ من عساه يكون" غير زامباي والبقيّة؟
Why are they coming from the sea side?
لِمَ كلّفوا أنفسهم المجيء من جانب البحر؟
Yeah... they usually come through the upper entrance...
نعم... بينما يستعملون المدخل ...الأعلى عادةً
Maybe they brought Straw Hat.
ربّما أحضروا قبّعة القش
Oh, that's right!
صحيح
I forgot I used you as bait to lure the Straw Hats here!
نسيت أنّني اتّخذتُك طُعمًا لإحضار قبّعة القش والبقية
They won't come. We're no longer friends.
لن يأتوا، ما عدنا رفاق
Didn't I tell you that?
ألم أخبرك؟
Why aren't they coming in?
لِمَ لا يدخلون؟
Okay, okay. I'll get the door!
حسنًا، حسنًا، سأفتح الباب الآن
Okay, okay... Hey, stop already!
قلتُ قادمة، توقّف عن قرع الجرس
Listen, little bro... Go back to your friends.
أخي... عد إلى رفاقك
I can't do that now. I dueled my captain.
،لا أستطيع فعل ذلك الآن خضتُ نزالاً مع قبطاني
Besides, the ship stuff isn't settled yet, so...
كما أنّني لم أنته بعد من تسوية ...الأمور مع السّفينة، لذا
What do you mean it hasn't been settled?
ماذا تقصد بأنّك لم تسوّ الأمور؟
If you know that your ship can't sail anymore, it's simple, ain't it?
الأمر بسيط بما أنّك تعرف أنّ السّفينة لا تستطيع الإبحار بعد الآن، أليس كذلك؟
Leave her with me.
دعها معي
I'll take care of her in a way that you'll appreciate.
سأعتني بها بطريقةٍ تُرضيك
And what I was doing earlier...
...ما فعلتُه سابقًا أيضًا
I figured taking apart the ship for you would be what's best.
حاولتُ تدمير السّفينة ظنًّا منّي أنّ ذلك هو الأفضل لك
Don't stick your nose into it! It's my business!
لا تحشر أنفك في أيّ شيء، هذا شأني
Hey, I'm trying to solve your problem!
إنّي أحاول حلّ مشكلتك
Zambai?
هل أنت زامباي؟
Be more appreciative!
عليك أن تقدّر ذلك
Appreciative? Give me a break!
عليّ تقدير ذلك؟ إليك عنّي
Don't you get it?! It's a nuisance for the ship too!
ألا تفهم؟ هذا مزعج بالنّسبة لتلك السّفينة أيضًا
She loves you guys so much that she appeared in human form.
إنّها تحبّكم حُبًّا جمًّا لدرجة أنّها ظهرت في شكل إنسان
If she sinks in the middle of the sea while you guys are on board...
إن غرقت في عرض البحر ...وأنتم على متنها
Hey! If that happens, even if she dies, she won't be able to rest in peace!
اسمع، إن حدث ذلك، حتّى إن ماتت ستموت وهي متحسّرة
Then, when your friends are dying, can you just leave them saying,
،إذًا عندما ترى رفاقك يموتون هل ستتركهم ببساطة وتقول
"Well, I hope you die without suffering at least"?!
آمل أن تموتوا دون أن تعانوا على الأقلّ"؟"
What you're suggesting is something else entirely!
إن قلتها بذلك السياق، فسيتغيّر النقاش كليًّا
Oh, please! This is exactly the same thing!
كلّا، لن يتغيّر، هذا هو الموضوع
What'll it take for you to get it, you...?!
لا تفهم فحسب، أليس كذلك؟
Mozu!
موزو
Kiwi!
كيوي
Pardon the interruption.
معذرةً... على مقاطعتكم
It's just, these two ladies didn't let us in, so...
...لكنّ هاتين الآنستان لم تدعانا ندخل، لذا
What the hell are you assholes doing here?!
ما الّذي تفعلونه هنا أيّها الأوغاد؟
Iron Body!
الجسد الحديدي
Huh? What the hell?!
أيّها الحقير
Blueno! What's the meaning of–
...بلونو، ما المعنى من
Huh? What's this? How cocky!
ما هذا؟ يا لتعجرفك
Who do you think I am?!
من تحسبني؟
You do know who you're picking a fight with, don't you?!
من تريد قتاله برأيك؟
You're just the owner of some sleazy tavern!
أنت مجرّد مالك حانة ممل
What's with that getup?!
ما قصة هذا الزّي؟
You're acting strange! What's going on?!
تبدو مختلفًا عن طبيعتك
Enough, Blueno.
إيّاك يا بلونو
H-Hey! A-Are you okay?!
أ-أنت، هل أنت بخير؟
We can't kill him yet. Don't forget our mission.
لا يمكننا قتله بعد، لا تنس مهمّتنا
Hang in there!
تماسك
Sorry.
آسف
Wh-Wh-What's going on?! Hey!
مـ-مـ-ما الّذي يجري؟ مهلاً
I swear I saw them working at the shipyard!
أنا واثق أنّني رأيتهم يعملون في حوض السفانة
What the hell? How did he...?
...ما هذا؟ كيف استطاع
What are you bastards?! You're sure acting pretty super, aren't you?!
أيّها الأوغاد، ما تكونون؟
How dare you hurt those innocent girls?! They're like my little sisters, you assholes!
كيف تجرؤون على إيذاء فتاتين بريئتين؟ إنّهما بمثابة أختَيّ الصّغيرتين أيّها الأنذال
And how do you even know about this place? This is my secret base!
وما أدراكم بهذا المكان من الأساس؟
None of that matters. I'll keep this simple, so listen carefully.
لا نأبه لذلك، سأبسّط هذا، لذا أنصت جيّدًا
Our lives in this town were a cover.
كانت حياتنا في هذه البلدة تستّرًا
But we are actually World Government intelligence agents.
أمّا في الحقيقة، نحن عملاء استخبارات حكومة العالم
You must know what that means...
...يجدر بك أن تعرف ما يعنيه ذلك
as well as the reason we came here.
وكذلك سبب مجيئنا إلى هنا
Franky, we already know everything.
فرانكي... نعرف كلّ شيء بالفعل
Cutty Flam...
...كاتي فلام
Tom's other disciple, who apparently died eight years ago...
تلميذ توم الثاني، الّذي قيل ...أنّه مات قبل ثمان سنوات
That's you.
إنّه أنت
I don't know how you found out, but that's pretty incredible.
لا أدري كيف عرفتم ذلك، لكن... هذا مذهل
At the same time, that's pretty unsettling.
لكن في نفس الوقت، أشعر بعدم الارتياح
Is that idiot Iceburg doing okay?
هل ذلك الغبيّ أيسبرغ بخير؟
We killed him.
قتلناه
Don't try to play dumb now...
...لا تحاول ادّعاء البراءة
We already know everything.
لأنّنا نعلم كلّ شيء بالفعل
It's only a matter of time before they come for me.
إنّها مسألة وقت قبل أن يستهدفوني
Take them and leave the island, Franky.
غادر هذه الجزيرة معهم... يا فرانكي
Tom handed them down to Iceburg... and Iceburg to you.
عهد بها توم لأيسبرغ والّذي بدوره عهدها لك
Both of you, come over here.
كلاكما، تعاليا إلى هنا
I wanna entrust something important to you two.
أريد أن أعهد لكما شيئًا مهمًّا
Our mission took quite a while, but it's finally checkmate.
استغرقت مهمّتنا طويلاً لكن ماتت الشاة أخيرًا
Now, hand over the blueprints for the ancient weapon Pluton, Cutty Flam.
والآن، سلّم لنا مخطّطات السلاح العتيق بلوتون يا كاتي فلام
Flam...? That's a strange name.
فلام...؟ إنّه اسم غريب
"Franky" ought to do, huh? "Franky" it is.
"فرانكي" سيفي بالغرض، صحيح؟ "فرانكي"
Anything is fine.
لا أهتم
Can you hear me?
ألا تسمعني؟
I'm saying hand them over, Cutty Flam.
أخبرتك أن تسلّمها لنا يا كاتي فلام
I've got nothing I could give you jerks!
لا أملك ما أمنحه لكم أيّها الأنذال
Wh-What just happened?! It was so fast I couldn't see a thing.
مـ-ماذا حدث توًّا؟ تمّ ذلك بسرعة لدرجة أنّني لم أستطع رؤية أيّ شيء
Hey! A-Are you okay?!
أنت، هل أنت بخير؟
This is...
...هذه
What's the matter, Lucci?
ما الخطب يا لوتشي؟
What is this filthy room?
ما هذه الغرفة القذرة؟
A drafting room?
غرفة تصميم؟
It's a good place to hide blueprints. Find them!
إنّه مكان جيّد لتخبئة المخطّطات، جدوها
These are... nameplates?
أهذه لوحات هويّة؟
Cutty Flam.
كاتي فلام
Iceburg.
أيسبرغ
Tom.
توم
This name is...
...هذا الاسم
This is...
...هذه
Don't you dare touch that!
إيّاك أن تلمسها
Don't just intrude on people's memories!
لا تتطفّلوا في ذكريات أحدهم
We were raised here.
هنا حيث كبرنا
This was the shipbuilding company, Tom's Workers, home of the world's best shipwright!
شركة السفانة، عُمّال توم